1969年3月3日 美国海军成立了一所精英学校
培训顶尖飞行员
目的是传授已失传的空战技巧
确保为数寥寥的学员在毕业后
成为精英级战斗机飞行员
他们取得了成效
如今 海军称之为战斗机武器学校
飞行员们则称之为：
壮志凌云：独行侠
今日的天气会异常炎热…
Today, we're looking at some of the hottest weather...
加利福尼亚 莫哈维沙漠
9马赫
彼得·独行侠·米契尔上校 试飞员
限制区
嘿
Hey.
怎么了？
What is it?
什么情况？
What?
我们接到禁飞命令
We've been ordered to stand down.
他们要取消这个项目
They're scrapping the program.
他们说我们没达标
They say we fell short.
合约门槛是10马赫
The contract threshold is mach 10.
10马赫是两个月后的事情
Mach 10 is supposed to be in two months.
今天的测试达标点是9马赫
Today's test point is mach 9.
这不够好
Well, that's not good enough.
谁说的？
Says who?
凯恩少将
Admiral Cain.
无人机游侠
The drone ranger.
他要为无人机项目挪用我们的预算
He wants our budget for his unmanned program.
他现在正赶来亲自终止试飞 并叫停我们的项目
He's on his way to kill the test and shut us down personally.
他不是还没到嘛
Well, he isn't here yet.
他们要10马赫
They want mach 10,
我们就给他们10马赫
let's give 'em mach 10.
独行侠
记住 合约门槛是10马赫
Now remember, the contract threshold is mach 10.
不是10.1或10.2 是10马赫
Not 10.1. Not 10.2. Mach 10.
这样项目就可以继续下去
That should keep the program alive.
我不喜欢你这种表情 独行侠
I Don't like that look, mav.
我只有这一种表情
It's the only one I got.
控制中心 我是暗星 能收到吗？
Control, this isdarkstar. How do you read?
这里是控制中心 通话清晰 我这边如何？
Darkstar, control. Loud and clear. How me?
通话清晰 完成飞前检查
Loud and clear. Takeoff precheck's complete. Ready for apu start.
启动辅助动力装置
启动左引擎
Ready left engine start.
启动右引擎
Ready right engine start.
滑行准备
Thumbs for taxi.
我们已经准备好开始滑行
We are ready for taxi.
塔台 我是暗星 滑行气候情况为阿尔法
Tower, this is darkstar. We are taxiing with information Alpha.
暗星 可以滑行
Darkstar, you are clear to taxi.
21跑道 风向210 风速10节
Runway 21. Winds 210, 10.
-油温正常 -控制中心同意
Fuel temps are looking good. control concurs.
电池量95% 舱压正常
Battery's holding at 95%. Cabin pressure looks good.
控制中心同意
Control concurs. Tower, this isdarkstar. We're ready for takeoff.
我是暗星 准备起飞
要求爬升至600英尺以上
Requesting an unrestricted climb to 600 and above.
暗星 尽管滑行起飞吧
Darkstar, the runway and skies are yours.
切斯特·凯恩少将
Rear admiral Chester Cain.
独行侠 凯恩到了大门
Maverick, Cain just pulled up to the gate.
叫停还来得及 老兄
It's not too late to stop, buddy.
你知道这么做会承担什么后果
You know what happens to you if you go through with this.
我只知道不这么做的话 其他人的下场会是怎样
I know what happens to everyone else if I Don't.
暗星准备起飞
Darkstar is ready for takeoff.
各位
Everyone,
准备起飞 先从引擎开始
go for takeoff, starting with engine.
-引擎 没问题 -热源影像系统 没问题
Engine, go. Thermals, go.
-燃油 没问题 -电力系统 没问题
Fuel, go. Electric, go.
控制面 没问题
Control surfaces, go.
暗星 控制中心 可以起飞了
Darkstar, control. You're cleared for takeoff.
好吧 宝贝
All right, sweetheart,
最后一次飞行
one last ride.
暗星 你可以爬升至600英尺后 加速到3.5马赫
Darkstar, you are cleared above 600. Increase to mach 3.5.
爬升至600英尺后加速到3.5马赫
Cleared above 600. Increase to mach 3.5.
少将
Admiral.
-来得刚好 长官 -我提早了 你也是
Uh, just in time, sir. I'm early. So are you.
可以解释一下吗？
You care to explain?
切换到超音速燃烧冲压引擎
Transitioning to scramjet.
凯恩少将要求…
Uh, mav, admiral Cain is asking...
-命令 -命令你立刻降落
Ordering. Ordering that we bring her down.
…爬升至六…
Within six...
通讯不稳定 长官
This is where we've had trouble with comms, sir.
因为地球曲面差 这叫地球隆起
It's the earth's curvature. It's called "earth bulge."
有人问过你喝不喝咖啡吗？
Did anyone offer you a coffee?
好的
Okay.
达到7马赫 逼近8马赫
He's at mach 7, pushing 8.
-飞行数据？-正在接收 数据没问题
Flight data? Receiving. Data is good.
油温升高 反馈仍然稳定
Temperature's climbing. Response is still stable. We're feeling good.
感觉很好
8.8马赫
Mach 8.8.
8.9
8.9.
9马赫
Mach 9.
他是世上最快的人
He's the fastest man alive.
你要在就好了 笨鹅
Talk to me, goose.
9.1马赫
Mach 9.1.
9.2
9.2.
9.3马赫
Mach 9.3.
9.4
9.4.
接近超高音速
Approaching high hypersonic.
挡风玻璃过热警告
Windshield hot caution.
机身表面温度升高
Surface temp rising.
快啊 宝贝 再快一点
Come on, sweetheart, just a little more.
只差一点了
Just a little.
快啊！
Come on!
10马赫！
Mach 10!
把这一笔加到国防预算里！
Put that in your Pentagon budget!
长官
Sir.
噢 不要 不要啊
Oh, Don't do it. Don't do it.
只要…
Just...
再加一把劲
A little push.
糟了
Holy shit.
这位飞行员 你还挺有种的
You got some balls, stick jockey.
我不得不承认
I'll give you that.
噢 糟糕
Oh, shit.
独行侠
Maverick.
独行侠！
Maverick!
谢谢
Thank you.
我在哪？
Where am I?
地球
Earth.
独行侠
Maverick.
在军队服役30多年
Thirty-plus years of service.
战功勋章
Combat medals.
奖项无数
Citations.
40年来唯一击落三架敌机的人
Only man to shoot down three enemy planes in the last 40 years.
杰出服役勋章
"Distinguished."
杰出服役勋章 还是杰出服役勋章
"Distinguished." "distinguished."
但你却升不了官 也不肯退役
Yet you can't get a promotion, you won't retire,
尽管多次出生入死 却又死不了
and despite your best efforts, you refuse to die.
即便当不了参议员 也早就该成为二星少将了
You should be at least a two-star admiral by now, if not a senator.
但你仍留在这里
Yet here you are:
当你的上校
Captain.
为什么？
Why is that?
人生总有谜团的嘛 长官
It's one of life's mysteries, sir.
这不是笑话 我在问你问题
This isn't a joke. I asked you a question.
我属于这里 长官
I'm where I belong, sir.
海军不这么认为
Well, the Navy doesn't see it that way.
不再如此了
Not anymore.
你试飞的战斗机
These planes you've been testing,
上校
captain,
迟早有一天 军队不再需要飞行员
one day, sooner than later, they won't need pilots at all.
需要吃喝拉撒睡的飞行员
Pilots that need to sleep, eat, take a piss.
违反命令的飞行员
Pilots that disobey orders.
你只是为其他人争取了一些时间
All you did was buy some time for those men out there.
未来已经来临
The future is coming,
而你不会参与其中
and you're not in it.
把这个人带出基地
Escort this man off the base.
到他的寝室 等着他打包
Take him to his quarters.
Wait with him while he packs his gear.
我需要他一小时内出发前往北岛航空站
I want him on the road to north island within the hour.
北岛航空站 长官？
North island, sir?
就在我开车过来 准备罚你永远禁飞那一刻
Call came in with impeccable timing,
有一通电话来得时机刚刚好
right as I was driving here to ground your ass once and for all.
我很不想说 但是
It galls me to say it, but...
只有老天和你的守护天使知道原因
For reasons known only to the almighty and your guardian angel...
你被召回高空利剑项目
You've been called back to topgun.
-长官？-解散 上校
Sir? You are dismissed, captain.
结局是无可避免的 独行侠
The end is inevitable, Maverick.
你这种飞行员总有一天会被淘汰
Your kind is headed for extinction.
也许吧 长官
Maybe so, sir.
但不是今天
But not today.
美国加利福尼亚圣地亚哥 战斗机城
海军航空部队 太平洋舰队
美国太平洋舰队司令 汤姆·冰人·卡赞斯基
彼得·独行侠·米契尔上校
Captain Pete "Maverick" Mitchell.
你可是声名远播
Your reputation precedes you.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
我没在表扬你
Wasn't a compliment.
我是博尔·辛普森中将
I'm admiral Beau Simpson. I'm the air boss.
航管指挥官 你应该认识贝兹少将
I believe you know admiral bates. Warlock, sir.
术士 长官
说实话 我没想到会受邀回来
Must admit, I wasn't expecting an invitation back.
这叫做命令 独行侠
They're called orders, Maverick.
你们俩有个共通点
You two have something in common.
旋风是1988届的第一名
Cyclone here was first in his class back in '88.
长官 其实我只是第二名
Actually, sir, I finished second.
别对我期望太高
Just want to manage expectations.
目标…
The target...
是一座违反多方北约协定
Is an unsanctioned uranium enrichment plant
未经批准的铀浓缩工厂
built in violation of a multilateral NATO treaty.
那里制造的铀对该地区的盟国
The uranium produced there represents a direct threat
造成直接威胁
to our allies in the region.
国防部要求我们召集突击队
The Pentagon has tasked us
with assembling a strike team and taking it out
在工厂运作前摧毁它
before it becomes fully operational.
工厂建在位于这座峡谷尽头的地下碉堡
The plant sits in an underground bunker at the end of this valley.
那座峡谷无法以GPS定位
Said valley is GPS-jammed
并有多枚地对空导弹发射器防卫
and defended by an extensive surface-to-air missile array
加上数架第五代战斗机
serving a limited number of fifth-generation fighters,
以及多架储备战斗机保卫领空
which in turn are backed up by a plentiful reserve of surplus aircraft.
甚至有几架老旧的F-14战斗机
Even a few old f-14s.
看来不是只有我们保留了老古董
Seems like we're not the only ones holding on to old relics.
你有什么想法 上校？
What's your read, captain?
通常出动F-35匿踪战斗机就能搞定
Well, sir, normally this would be a cakewalk for the f-35's stealth,
但无法以GPS定位就没办法了
but the GPS-jamming negates that.
地对空导弹的存在 只能用F-18
And a surface-to-air threat necessitates a low-level laser-guided strike
以低空激光引导攻击
tailor-made for the f-18.
我认为
I figure,
最少要投掷两枚精准炸弹
two precision bombs, minimum.
两架一组 出动四架战斗机
Makes it four aircraft flying in pairs.
飞离峡谷必须垂直爬升
That is one hell of a steep climb out of there,
暴露在地对空导弹攻击范围内
exposing you to all the surface-to-air missiles.
就算幸存下来
You survive that,
回程也得一路和敌机交战
it's a dogfight all the way home.
你拥有这一切的实战经验
All requirements for which you have real-world experience.
并不全在同一项任务中 长官
Not in the same mission, sir.
不
No.
并不是 有人会无法活着回来
No, someone's not coming back from this.
到底可不可行？
Can it be done or not?
工厂还有多久就会开始运作？
How soon before the plant becomes operational?
还有三周时间 或许更少
Three weeks. Maybe less.
我很久没开F-18战斗机 而且…
Well, it's been a while since i've flown an f-18, and...
我不确定能否信任另外三名飞行员
I'm not sure who i'd trust to fly the other three.
但我会想出办法完成任务
But i'll find a way to make it work.
你误会了 上校
I think you misunderstand, captain.
长官？
Sir?
我们不要你飞 而是要你教飞行
We Don't want you to fly it.
We want you to teach it.
教飞行 长官？
Teach, sir?
我们从各中队召回12名高空利剑毕业学员
We've recalled 12 topgun graduates from their squadrons.
你要从中选出6名飞行员
We want you to narrow that pool down to six.
让他们执行飞行任务
They'll fly the mission.
有问题吗 上校？
Is there a problem, captain?
你明知道有 长官
You know there is, sir.
对
Yeah.
布莱德利·布雷德萧 人称公鸡
Bradley bradshaw, aka "rooster."
我知道你和他爸曾是搭档
I understand you used to fly with his old man.
他的呼号是什么？
What was his call sign?
笨鹅 长官
"Goose," sir.
那件事确实很不幸
Tragic what happened.
米契尔上校被裁定没犯错
Captain Mitchell was cleared of any wrongdoing.
笨鹅的死是意外
Goose's death was an accident.
你是这么想吗？
Is that how you see it, captain?
笨鹅的儿子也是这么想吗？
Is that how goose's son sees it?
恕我直言 长官 我不是当教官的料
With all due respect, sir, i'm not a teacher.
你当过高空利剑教官
You were a topgun instructor before.
那是30年前了 只撑了两个月
That was almost 30 years ago. I lasted two months.
我不是这块料
It's not where I belong.
我实话实说吧
Then let me be perfectly blunt.
你不是我的第一选择 实际上你根本不在名单上
You were not my first choice. In fact, you weren't even on the list.
你能来这里 是因为卡赞斯基上将要求的
You are here at the request of admiral kazansky.
我非常景仰冰人
Now, iceman happens to be a man I deeply admire,
他认为你对海军仍能有所贡献
and he seems to think that you have something left to offer the Navy.
我想不出是什么
What that is, I can't imagine.
你不必接下这工作
You Don't have to take this job.
但请恕我直言：
But let me be clear:
这会是你最后一项任务 上校
This will be your last post, captain.
你要么当高空利剑的教官 要么就退出海军
You fly for topgun, or you Don't fly for the Navy ever again.
我赌20美元你不能连续正中靶心三次
Twenty bucks you can't get three in a row.
冰人：会面进行得不太顺利
那孩子还没能准备好执行这项任务
冰人：没有人能准备好
所以才会把你找来
你可以提前打个招呼啊
冰人：那你还会来吗？
不会吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
彼得
Pete.
潘妮？
Penny?
-你在这里做什么？-这话该我问你
What are you doing here?
I should ask you the same thing.
-说来话长 -我不信
Well, that is a long story. I doubt that.
是啊
Yeah.
你这次又惹到了谁？
Who'd you piss off this time?
另一位少将
Another admiral.
那就对了
Exactly.
-你这是在生我气吗？-彼得
Are you mad at me? Oh, Pete.
我没办法一直生你气 这才是问题
I can never stay mad at you. That's the problem.
我得说
I got to say, north island is the one place
我以为永远不会在北岛航空站碰到你
I thought for sure i'd never run into you.
-你来这边多久了？-我三年前买下这地方
Mmm. How long you been here?
Bought this place about three years ago.
-三年前？-是啊
Three years? Mm-hmm. Yeah.
就在你惹了另一位少将被派去沙漠之后
Not long after you got shipped off to the desert for pissing off that other admiral.
那是三年前的事？
That was three years ago?
你一定惹上了大麻烦
You must be in a lot of trouble.
你才不会自愿回来这里
No way you'd come back here willingly.
不过嘛
Well,
你会想办法解决
you'll sort it out.
不 我想…
No, I think, uh...
-这是最后一次 -拜托
I think this is it. Come on, Pete.
我认识你以后你就一直这么说
You've been saying that as long as i've known you.
你开F-18载我兜风被逮到也这么说
You said it after they busted you for taking me on a joyride in that f-18.
没过多久你就被派去波斯尼亚
Then the next thing I know, you're off to Bosnia.
然后去伊拉克 两次都如此
Then Iraq. Both times.
你每次惹上麻烦
You get yourself in trouble,
只要冰人打通电话 你又能飞了
iceman makes a call, and you're back in the air.
潘妮 这次不同
Penny, this is different.
彼得 相信我
Pete, trust me,
也许现在看似不可能
as improbable as it seems right now,
但你一定会再坐上战斗机搞出什么花样来
somehow you'll be back in a fighter plane with your tail on fire.
-潘妮… -太迟了
Penny... too late.
什么？
What?
你本来要问我几点下班
You were about to ask me what time I get off.
别用那副表情看我
Don't give me that look.
我没用什么表情看你 我发誓
I'm not giving you any look. I swear.
我们每次的结局都一样 彼得
It always ends the same with us, Pete.
这次就别重蹈覆辙了
Let's not start this time.
好吧
Okay.
你看起来挺好的
You look good.
多谢了 老兄
Much appreciated, pal.
有什么我不知道的事吗？
What am I missing?
冒犯女士 海军 或把手机放吧台
"Disrespect a lady, the Navy, or put your cell phone on my bar..."
就得请一轮酒
"And you buy a round."
请每一个人？
For everyone?
恐怕规矩不能破 幸好时候还早
I'm afraid rules are rules. You're lucky it's early.
拜托！
Oh, come on!
看看谁来了？
What do we have here?
这不是凤凰嘛！
If it ain't Phoenix!
我本来还以为我们有多特别呢 郊狼
And here I thought we were special, coyote.
没想到随便谁都会被请到这里
Turns out the invite went to anyone.
各位 这位是包子手
Fellas, this here's bagman.
-刽子手 -随便吧
Hangman.whatever.
他可是唯一一名曾在空战中 击落过敌机的
You're looking at the only naval aviator on active duty
海军飞行员
with a confirmed air-to-air kill.
别说了
Stop.
不过对方开的是韩战时期的古董战斗机
Mind you, the other guy was in a museum piece
from the korean war.
-冷战 -不同的战争 同一个世纪
Cold war. Different wars, same century.
不是这个世纪
Not this one.
你朋友是谁？
Who are your friends?
-复仇者 -粉小子
Payback.fanboy.
-嘿 郊狼 -嘿
Hey, coyote.Hey.
-他是谁？-谁是谁？
Who's he? Who's who?
你什么时候进来的？
When did you get in?
我一直都在这里
Oh, i've been here the whole time.
-他是开隐形战斗机的 -他是真能隐形啊
The man's a stealth pilot.Literally.
我是武器系统操作官
Weapons systems officer, actually.
毫无幽默感
With no sense of humor.
他们叫你什么？
What do they call you?
鲍勃
Bob.
不是的 你的呼号
No, your call sign.
鲍勃
Bob.
鲍勃·弗洛伊德
Bob Floyd.
你就是我新的武器官？勒莫尔来的那位
You're my new backseater? From lemoore?
看来是这样 对啊
Looks like it. Yeah.
打一场台球吧 鲍勃
Nine-ball, Bob.
把球摆好
Rack 'em.
好吧
Okay.
-亲爱的潘妮 -是
Penny, my dear. yeah.
再来四杯啤酒 老家伙请客
I'll have four more on the old-timer.
布雷德萧！
Bradshaw!
是你吗？
Is that you?
你回美国竟然都不打声招呼？
This is how I find out you're stateside?
对啊 我想给你个惊喜
Yeah, I just thought i'd surprise you.Hmm.
那我也给你个惊喜吧
I guess I surprised you back.
-见到你真好 -我也是
It's good to see you. Good to see you too.
-拿好 -谢谢
Here you go. thank you.
谢啦 老爹
Much appreciated, pops.
趁着人还不算太多 先帮我结帐吧
How about ringing me up before the evening rush?
布雷德萧
Bradshaw.
真是不敢相信
As I live and breathe.
刽子手
Hangman.
你看起来…挺帅
You look... good.
当然了 公鸡
Well, I am good, rooster.
我本来就很帅
I'm very good.
其实
In fact,
我简直帅到不真实
I am too good to be true.
那么
So,
有人知道为什么把我们找回来吗？
anybody know what this special detachment is all about?
任务就是任务 我不问原因
No, mission's a mission. They Don't confront me.
我只想知道谁会是队长？
What I want to know: Who's gonna be team leader?
你们几个有谁够资格跟我出任务？
And which one of y'all
has what it takes to follow me?
刽子手 跟你只会早点进坟墓
Hangman, the only place you'll lead anyone is an early grave.
而跟你只会耗尽燃油
Well, anyone who follows you is just gonna run out of fuel.
但你就是这风格 对吧 公鸡？
But that's just you, ain't it, rooster?
你只会窝在驾驶舱
You're snug on that perch,
等着永远都不会来的...
waiting for just the right moment...
完美机会
That never comes.
我超爱这首歌！
I love this song!
他一点都没变
Well, he hasn't changed.
没错 还是那副样子
Nope. Sure hasn't.
瞧瞧啊
Check it out.
又来了几波人
More patches.
哈佛、耶鲁、奥马哈 该死 那是弗里茨
That's Harvard, Yale, Omaha. Shit, that's Fritz.
这到底是什么任务？
What the hell kind of mission is this?
我们不该问这问题
That's not the question we should be asking.
大家都是顶尖高手
Everyone here is the best there is.
谁能厉害到当我们的教官？
Who the hell are they gonna get to teach us?
卡被拒了
It's been declined.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding.
嘿 各位 过来
Hey, guys. Come on.
我不如付…
How about...
钱不够
That won't cover it.
我明天带现金过来
Uh, i'll come by tomorrow and bring you the cash.
恐怕规矩不能破 彼得
I'm afraid rules are rules, Pete.
丢出去！
Overboard! Overboard! Overboard!
真的吗？
Really?
丢出去！
Overboard! Overboard!
见到你真好 彼得！
Great to see you, Pete! Overboard!
丢出去！
Overboard! Overboard!
多谢你请我们喝啤酒！欢迎再次光临！
Thanks for the beers! Come back anytime!
你撩动我的心 扰乱我神志
You shake my nerves and you rattle my brain
太浓烈的爱会让人痴狂
too much love drives a man insane
你摧毁我的意志 我却因你痴狂
you broke my will but what a thrill
我的老天 多大一团火焰！
goodness gracious great balls of fire!
我曾嘲笑爱情 我以为那很可笑
I laughed at love 'cause I thought it was funny
但亲爱的 你的出现打动了我的心
but you came along and you moved me, honey
我改变了想法 这场爱情很美好
I changed my mind this love is fine
我的老天 多大一团火焰！
goodness gracious great balls of fire!
吻我吧 宝贝
Kiss me, baby
我的老天 多大一团火焰！
goodness gracious great balls of fire!
高度八千英尺…七千英尺…
Altitude 8,000... 7,000...
笨鹅 我抓不到弹射把手
Goose, I can't reach the ejection handle.
弹射！
Eject, eject, eject!
笨鹅！不！
Goose! Oh, no!
天啊 他真的很爱跟你一起飞 独行侠
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick.
全体立正！
Attention on deck!
早上好
Morning.
欢迎参加特训营
Welcome to your special training detachment.
坐
Be seated.
我是贝兹少将 航空作战中心指挥官
I'm admiral bates, nawdc commander.
你们都是高空利剑毕业生
You're all topgun graduates.
精英飞行员
The elite.
高手中的高手
The best of the best.
那都是过去式了
That was yesterday.
敌人全新的第五代战斗机 对我们形成了制约
The enemy's new fifth-generation fighter has leveled the playing field.
细节不多 但要知道
Details are few, but you can be sure
我们不再拥有科技的优势
we no longer possess the technological advantage.
获胜与否从未如此取决于
Success, now more than ever,
驾驶舱内的男女飞行员
comes down to the man or woman in the box.
你们有一半会入选
Half of you will make the cut.
其中一个会是任务队长
One of you will be named mission leader.
另一半则是预备飞行员
The other half will remain in reserve.
你们的教官是一位高空利剑校友
Your instructor is a topgun graduate
他拥有你们必须掌握这次任务的
with real-world experience in every mission aspect
实战经验技巧
you will be expected to master.
他的丰功伟业堪称传奇
His exploits are legendary.
他是这个项目有史以来
And he's considered to be one of the finest pilots
其中一位最优秀的飞行员
this program has ever produced.
他要教导的内容
What he has to teach you
极可能会关乎你们的生死
may very well mean the difference between life and death.
容我介绍彼得·米契尔上校
I give you captain Pete Mitchell.
呼号是独行侠
Call sign: "Maverick."
早上好
Good morning.
F-18战斗机训练及标准操作程序
The f-18 natops.
包含了你们应该知道的一切
It contains everything they want you to know about your aircraft.
我猜你们都背得滚瓜烂熟
I'm assuming you know the book inside and out.
-没错 -当然
Damn right. Damn straight.
绝对的
You got it.
你们的敌人也是
So does your enemy.
这下有意思了
And we're off.
敌人不知道的是你们的极限
But what the enemy doesn't know is your limits.
我打算找到它们
I intend to find them,
加以考验
test them,
鞭策你们超越极限
push beyond.
今天就先从你们自以为知道的内容开始
Today we'll start with what you only think you know.
让我看看你们的能耐
You show me what you're made of.
公鸡
Rooster.
布拉德利
Bradley.
布雷德萧中尉！
Lieutenant bradshaw!
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们之间没必要这样
Let's not do it like this.
你会把我刷下来吗？
You gonna wash me out?
那要看你 不是看我
That'll be up to you, not me.
我可以走了吗？
Am I dismissed?
早上好 飞行员 我是你们的上校
Good morning, aviators. This is your captain speaking.
欢迎参加基本飞行训练
Welcome to basic fighter maneuvers.
今天要操练的是空战
As briefed, today's exercise is dogfighting.
只用机关枪 不用导弹
Guns only, no missiles.
限低不能低于五千英尺
We do not go below the hard deck of 5,000 feet.
两架战斗机一组 将我击落 否则
Working as a team, you have to shoot me down, or else.
-否则怎样？-我会反击
Or else what, sir? Or else I shoot back.
只要击落一架战斗机 两架都算输
If I shoot either one of you down, you both lose.
这家伙太自大了
This guy needs an ego check. We'll see to that.
交给我们吧
-不如来赌一把 -你想赌什么？
What say we put some skin in the game? What do you have in mind?
先被击落做两百下俯卧撑
Whoever gets shot down first has to do 200 push-ups.
各位 这可是不少下俯卧撑
Guys. That's a lot of push-ups.
训练可不是闹着玩的 长官
They Don't call it an exercise for nothing, sir.
那就一言为定 先生们
You got yourself a deal, gentlemen.
开战了 豁出去了
Fight's on. Let's turn and burn.
粉小子 看到他吗？
Fanboy, you see him? Nothing on radar up ahead.
他不在前方 一定在后面
He must be somewhere behind us.
-我去！-搞什么？
Damn it! What the hell?
该死！
Shit!
慢点来 独行侠
Easy, Maverick.
别在第一天就被炒鱿鱼
Let's try not to get fired on the first day.
看见目标 独行侠逼近！向左急转！
Tally, tally, tally! Maverick's coming in! Break left!
向左急转
Breaking left.
复仇者 你的僚机呢？
Payback, where's your wingman?
-公鸡 你在哪？-有我呢
Rooster, where are you? I got your back.
我来了 撑着点
I'm coming. Hang in there. Hang in there.
快点！
Hurry up, man! Hurry up!
-复仇者 向右急转 -向右急转
Payback, break right. Breaking right.
公鸡救了你们 但他会付出代价
Rooster just saved your life, fellas. But it's gonna cost him.
这次不行 老人家
Not this time, old man.
别被他激怒 独行侠
Don't let him get to you, Maverick.
公鸡 你飞得太低！快爬升！
Rooster, you're too low! Pull up! You're hitting the hard deck!
-高度 -糟糕
Altitude. Altitude. oh, shit.
你被击落了
That's a kill.
身子下去！109下
Down! 109. we Don't get fooled again
身子下去！110下
Down! 110.
那应该是我们
That should be us down there. 111!
但并不是
But it's not. Down!
现在你对公鸡也有所了解了
And now you know a little something about rooster.
留守在跑道 等我们回来
Whoo! Wow.
Hold that tarmac down till we get back, brother, all right?
拍一张 大伙儿
Get in there, boys.
-你被击落了 -该死！
That's a kill. Damn!
-被击落了 -该死
Smoked. Damn it.
刚才自拍得很开心嘛 身子下去！
It was all fun and games in that selfie, wasn't it? Down!
我说 凤凰
Say, Phoenix.
不如我们告诉大家鲍勃是什么的简称？
How's about we tell everybody
"Bob" stands for something?
-除了罗伯特之外 -别上当 鲍勃
Other than Robert, I mean. Don't take the bait, Bob.
想知道他为什么叫刽子手吗？
Want to know why we call him hangman?
我想到了 宝宝啵啵
I got it. "Baby on board."
我去！
Shit!
各位飞行员好 开战了
Greetings, aviators. Fight's on.
凤凰 把这家伙击落！
All right, Phoenix, let's take this guy out!
小心后方 凤凰
Watch your back, Phoenix.
-向右急转！-向右急转
Break right! Breaking right.
他这是去哪？
Where's he going?
他是刽子手 只会害死你
That's why we call him hangman.
He'll always hang you out to dry.
丢下你的僚机兄弟不管
Leaving your wingman.
很久没看过这一招了
There's a strategy I haven't seen in a while.
竟然说僚机兄弟 凤凰 你忍得了他把你当男人看吗？
He called you a man, Phoenix. You gonna take that?
只要他别把你当人看就行
So long as he doesn't call you a man.
汇报情况 鲍勃 独行侠在哪？
Talk to me, Bob. Where's Maverick?
天啊 他已经绕回来了！
Jesus, his nose is already coming around!
帮我甩掉他 刽子手！
Get him off me, hangman!
各位基地的战友们 看我怎么埋了这化石
For all you folks at home, this is how you Bury a fossil.
刽子手 该教训教训你了
All right, hangman. Time to teach you a lesson.
-你出局了 凤凰 -真是混蛋！
You're out, Phoenix. Son of a bitch!
你完蛋了
That's it.
-来吧 独行侠 看你有多厉害 -来追我啊
Let's go, mav. Let's see what you got.
Come get me.
恶魔退下 刽子手来也
Evil be gone. Hangman's coming.
行 我得承认 你还挺厉害的
Yeah, you're good. I'll give you that.
该死 凤凰 我看不到他 我离他多近？
same as the old bossshit.
Phoenix, I can't see him. How close am I?
-凤凰？-我已经死了 混蛋
Phoenix? I'm dead, dickhead.
下辈子再见 包子手
See you in the afterlife, bagman.
他在哪？
Where is he? Where is he?
你死了
That's a kill.
79 身子下去 80 身子下去
Seventy-nine. Down. Eighty. Down.
来吧 下一个是谁？
Let's go. Who's next?
-锁定你了 奥马哈 -可恶！
I got you, Omaha. Damn it!
-你出局了 郊狼 -收到 本人已挂
Lights out, coyote. Copy kill.
身子下去 51 身子下去 52
Down. Fifty-one. Down. Fifty-two.
公鸡 能问你个私人问题吗？
So, rooster, mind if I ask you a personal question?
我介意你就不问了吗？
Would it matter if I did?
你和独行侠有什么过节？
What's the story with you and Maverick?
-你好像看他很不顺眼 -不关你的事
It seems like he's got you rattled. That's none of your business.
他到底在哪？
Now where the hell is he?
一直都在这里
Been here the whole time.
好家伙
Holy shit.
看到我了吗？
You see me now?
来吧 速战速决
Come on, let's get it over with.
开战了！
Fight's on!
那两个人到底是怎么回事？
What is with these two?
你逼我们成了这种局面 你要怎么给自己解围？
All right, you put us here. How you gonna get yourself out?
你随时都能撤
You can bail out anytime.
你想俯冲到多低 公鸡？
How low you want to go, rooster?
比你的底线更低 长官 你懂我意思
I can go as low as you, sir! And that's saying something.
过去的就让它过去吧 我们俩都不要纠结
What's past is past. For both of us.
你倒想这样 对吧？
You'd like to believe that, wouldn't you?
各位 限低是五千英尺 就快到了
Hard deck is 5,000 feet, fellas. You are running out of room.
高度
Altitude. Your strategy is about to run us into the ground.
你的战术就要害我们都坠机了
-你到底在打什么算盘？-高度
What's your move? Altitude. Altitude.
高度
Altitude.
Altitude. Altitude. Altitude.
高度
Altitude. Altitude.
爬升！爬升啊！
Pull up! Pull up! Pull up! Pull up!
爬升！
Pull up! Pull up!
你行的 别多想 做就是了
You got it. Don't think, just do.
快啊 公鸡 你逮到他了！飞到下方然后射击！
Come on, rooster, you got him! Drop down and take the shot!
太低了
It's too low.
太迟了 你错过机会了
Too late. You had your chance.
你被击落了 到此为止吧
That's a kill. Knock it off.
该死！
Damn it!
还是老样子的公鸡
Same old rooster.
去找杭多做俯卧撑吧
Go see hondo about your push-ups.
好了 够了
All right, that's enough.
公鸡 够了
Rooster. That's enough, man.
突破限低 不服从命令 你想被踢走吗？
Breaking the hard deck, insubordination. Are you trying to get kicked out?
别担心
Don't worry about it.
这项任务我去定了
Look, i'm going on this mission.
但如果你被踢走 我就得和刽子手一起飞
But if you get kicked out, you leave us flying with hangman.
-跟我说说 到底是怎么回事？-他抽掉了我的档案
Talk to me. What the hell was that? He pulled my papers.
-什么？谁？-独行侠
What? Who? Maverick.
他抽掉了我在海军学院的申请书
He pulled my application to the naval academy.
害我浪费了四年
Set me back four years.
他为什么要这么做？
Why would he do that?
限低是五千英尺
The hard deck is 5,000 feet above ground level.
不只是为了飞行员的安全
A parameter is set not just for the safety of our pilots,
也是为了保全他们所驾驶的战斗机
but for the safety of their aircraft.
五千英尺不只是规定 更是一条铁律 不可违抗
5,000 feet is not just a rule. It is a law, as immutable as gravity.
这项任务的限低会更低 长官
The hard deck will be much lower for the mission, sir.
没我的允许不准更改！
And it will not change without my approval!
尤其是在演练的时候
Especially not in the middle of an exercise.
你那套眼镜蛇花招会害死你们三个
And that cobra maneuver of yours? That could've got all three of you killed.
我不想再看到那种破事
I never want to see that shit again.
你以为你在教什么 上校？
What exactly do you suppose you were teaching, captain?
长官 他们虽然很优秀 但还有得要学
That as good as they are, sir, they still have something to learn.
他们可是世上最顶尖的飞行员 上校
You are talking about the best fighter pilots on the planet, captain.
他们在职业生涯中一直都被这样吹捧
And they've been told that their entire career,
却只会从高空投掷炸弹
while they've been dropping bombs from a high altitude
没有空中缠斗的经验
with little to no dogfighting.
这是他们从来没有执行过的任务
The parameters of this mission call for something they have never encountered.
你只有不到三周要教会他们 如何在战斗中进行团队合作
Okay, you have less than three weeks to teach them how to fight as a team
还有击中目标
and how to strike the target.
也要活着回来
And how to come home.
必须活着回来 长官
And how to come home, sir.
每项任务都有风险
Every mission has its risks.
这些飞行员都能接受
These pilots accept that.
我不接受 长官
I Don't, sir.
从今天起 每天早上
Every morning, from this day forward,
你要书面报告你的作战教学计划
you will brief us on your instructional plans in writing.
没有我的允许不准做出更动
And nothing will change without my express approval.
-包括限低？-尤其是限低 上校
Including the hard deck, sir? Especially the hard deck, captain.
长官
Sir.
这是什么？
What is this?
要求降低限低的申请书 长官
It's a request to lower the hard deck, sir,
为了演练低空轰炸任务
to practice a low-level bombing run per the mission parameters.
有关时机的掌控要多注意点 上校
You could learn a thing or two about timing, captain.
我说 郊狼
Yo, coyote.
瞧瞧这个
Take a look at this.
传奇人物 就是他
The man, the legend. There he is.
不是 他旁边那个
No, no, no. Next to him.
你觉得眼熟吗？
He look familiar to you?
这什么情况？
What have we here?
布雷德萧
Bradshaw.
真是不敢相信
As I live and breathe.
西奥 你长大了
Hey, Theo, you got big.
嘿 独行侠
Hey, mav.
阿米莉亚？
Amelia?
我知道 我长大了
I know. I got big.
是啊
Yes.
酒吧五点才开
Bar opens at 5:00.
不是 我只是来还钱的
No, I just came by to pay off a debt.
妈！
Mom!
-你爸好吗？-在夏威夷 跟他老婆一起
Hey, how's your dad? With his wife, in Hawaii.
妈！
Mom!
独行侠说他欠你钱
Mav says he owes you money.
-不用还了 -我坚持
Oh. Don't worry about it. I insist.
谢了 上校 酒帐还清了
Thank you, captain. Consider your tab closed.
还是上校？
Captain? Still?
屡获战功的上校
A highly decorated captain.
先把你的作业写完
Finish up.
我们得把船开到船坞
We have to get the boat to the yard.
-我去不了 -什么叫你去不了？
I can't go. What do you mean, you can't go?
明天要测试 我得复习 今天才告诉我们的
Test tomorrow. I have to study. They only told us today.
我不能一个人驾驶帆船
Well, I can't sail her alone.
那就用引擎啊
Just use the engine.
为什么要开到船坞？
Why are we taking her to the yard?
为了修理引擎
To fix the engine.
我能帮忙
Mm-hmm. I can help.
-浪比我预期的更大 -看得出来
Little rougher than I was expecting. You Don't say.
拉住控帆索 减低风力
Pull on the backstay. We'll de-power the sails.
好
Okay.
那什么意思？
What does that mean?
你不是海军吗？
You're supposed to be in the Navy!
我不会开船 潘妮 只会降落在航母
I Don't sail boats, penny. I land on them.
这就像打开飞机襟翼一样
It's sort of like raising the flaps on an airplane.
我要怎么做？
So how do I do that?
拉住那条绿绳索
You pull on that green line up there.
绿绳索
Green line.
对 用力拉
Yep. Pull it hard.
对 用力转那个曲柄
Yep. Crank that winch right there,
拉紧三角帆
tighten the jib.
-用力转 你还好吗？-没问题
Crank it. You okay? Yeah.
很好
Good.
现在
Now,
准备好了吗？
you ready?
准备好什么？
For what?
加力风帆
The afterburner.
现在你才算是海军
Now you're in the Navy.
今天谢谢你帮忙
Thanks for helping out today.
我好像没帮到什么
I'm not exactly sure I helped.
别甩给我那副表情
Don't give me that look.
什么表情？
What look?
那副表情
That one.
晚安 彼得
Good night, Pete.
晚安 潘妮
Night, penny.
妈 是你吗？
Mom, is that you?
对啊
Yeah, it's me.
我来给你做晚饭
I'll make you dinner.
好
Okay.
抵达目标时间 3分钟
时间是最大的敌人
Time is your greatest enemy.
任务第一阶段是低空进入
Phase one of the mission will be a low-level ingress
两架战斗机一组进行攻击
attacking in two-plane teams.
沿着狭窄的峡谷飞至目标
You'll fly along this narrow canyon to your target.
雷达导引地对空导弹防卫该地区
Radar-guided surface-to-air missiles defend the area.
这些地对空导弹 极度致命
These sams, they're lethal.
但它们负责防御领空 不是峡谷
But they were designed to protect the skies above, not the canyon below.
因为敌人知道没人会疯狂到飞进峡谷
That's because the enemy knows no one is insane enough to try and fly below them.
我就是要训练你们这么做
That's exactly what i'm gonna train you to do.
任务当天的飞行高度最多100英尺
On the day, your altitude will be 100 feet maximum.
超过这高度就会被雷达侦测
You exceed this altitude...
Radar will spot you
你就死定了
and you're dead.
飞行速度是660节
Your airspeed will be 660 knots
最低速度
minimum.
抵达目标时间是两分半钟
Time to target: Two and a half minutes.
因为第五代战斗机在附近军用机场待命
That's because fifth-generation fighters wait at an air base nearby.
F-18战斗机对上它们 你就死定了
In a head-to-head with these planes in your f-18s, you're dead.
你们得飞进峡谷 击中目标
That's why you need to get in, hit your target and be gone
趁那些战斗机尚未抵达时飞离敌区
before these planes even have a chance of catching you.
这样的话 时间就变成了最大的敌人
This makes time your greatest adversary.
你们要照着模拟峡谷的航道飞行
You'll fly a route in your nav system that simulates the canyon.
越快飞过峡谷
The faster you navigate this canyon,
就越难被敌军控制地对空导弹的 雷达侦测到
the harder it'll be to stay under the radar of these enemy sams.
弯度越窄
The tighter the turns,
身体承受的G力就越大
the more intensely the force of gravity
on your body multiplies...
肺部受到挤压
Compressing your lungs...
血液离开大脑
Forcing the blood from your brain...
降低判断 并影响反应时间
Impairing your judgment and reaction time.
今天的训练比较轻松
So for today's lesson, we're gonna take it easy on you.
最大高度：三百英尺 目标时间：三分钟
Max ceiling: 300 feet. Time to target: Three minutes.
祝好运
Good luck.
目标时间一分半钟
Time to target is one minute 30.
我们落后两秒 加速到480节
We are two seconds behind. Increase to 480 knots.
我们得快点 郊狼
We got to move, coyote.
收到 加速中
Copy. Increasing speed.
噢 该死！
Oh, shit!
他们怎么会死？
Why are they dead?
我们超过300英尺 一枚地对空导弹击落了我们
We broke the 300-foot ceiling, and a Sam took us out.
不对 他们怎么会死？
No. Why are they dead?
我减速却没警告她 是我的错
I slowed down and didn't give her a warning. It was my fault.
你为什么没警告队友？
Was there a reason you didn't communicate with your team? I was focusing on...
我正在专心…
说出他们的家人在葬礼上能接受的理由
One that their family will accept at the funeral.
我没有 长官
None, sir.
你熟知地形 怎么不知道要急转？
Why didn't you anticipate the turn?
You were briefed on the terrain.
别告诉我 告诉他的家人
Don't tell me. Tell it to his family.
刽子手 慢点 峡谷越来越窄
Hangman, ease up. The canyon's getting tighter.
不行 复仇者 你要加速
Negative, payback. Increase your speed.
-你飞得太快 -提早完成也没什么不好的
You're going too fast, man. No harm in being ahead of schedule.
该死 慢点！我无法留在航道！
Damn it, slow down! I can't stay on the course!
你会撞上山壁！小心！
You're gonna hit the wall! Watch out! Watch out!
-怎么回事？-我飞到最快
What happened? I flew as fast as I could.
尽最大努力
Kind of like my ass depended on it.
你危及到队友 僚机也挂了
And you put your team in danger, and your wingman's dead.
是他们跟不上我
They couldn't keep up.
公鸡 我们落后20秒 而且还在落后
Rooster, we're 20 seconds behind and dropping.
我们没事 速度没问题
We're fine. Speed is good.
加速到500节
Increase to 500 knots.
-不 耶鲁 别加速 -公鸡 我们落后了！
Negative, Yale. Hold your speed. rooster, we're late!
我们还活着 直飞时再赶进度
We're alive. We'll make up time in the straightaway.
我们会来不及
We are not gonna make it.
相信我 保持速度 赶得到的
Just trust me. Maintain your speed. We can make it.
你为什么会死？
Why are you dead?
你是队长 你和队友为什么会死？
You're team leader up there.
Why are you, why is your team dead?
长官 只有他抵达目标
Sir, he's the only one who made it to the target.
迟了一分钟
A minute late.
他给敌机时间击落他
He gave enemy aircraft time to shoot him down.
-他死了 -这你可说不准
He is dead. You Don't know that.
你飞得太慢 一秒都不能浪费
You're not flying fast enough. You Don't have a second to waste.
我们成功抵达目标了
We made it to the target.
在你返航时 性能更优越的敌机拦截了你
And superior enemy aircraft intercepted you on your way out.
-那就来场空战啊 -对抗第五代战斗机
Then it's a dogfight. Against fifth-generation fighters.
-还是有机会 -F-18战斗机赢不了
Yeah. We'd still have a chance. in an f-18.
关键不是在战斗机 长官 而是飞行员
It's not the plane, sir, it's the pilot.
没错！
Exactly!
执行这次飞行任务还有其他方法
There's more than one way to fly this mission.
你真的没搞懂
You really Don't get it.
执行这任务就得像独行侠那样飞
On this mission, a man flies like Maverick here,
否则就不可能活着回来
or a man does not come back.
无意冒犯
No offense intended.
但不知何故 你却总是冒犯到我们
Yet somehow you always manage.
我不是批评你 只是你太保守了
Look, I Don't mean to criticize.
You're conservative, that's all.Lieutenant.
中尉
小子 我们将要进行的空战 没有其他飞行员尝试过
We're going into combat, son, on a level no living pilot's ever seen.
就连他也没有
Not even him.
没时间纠结过去的事
That's no time to be thinking about the past.
-你这话什么意思？-公鸡
What's that supposed to mean? Rooster.
不可能只有我知道他爸和独行侠一起飞过
I can't be the only one that knows that Maverick flew with his old man.
-够了 -或者说独行侠在飞行的时候
That's enough. Or that Maverick was flying when his old man...
-害他爸… -中尉 够了！
Lieutenant, that's enough!
-够了 -你这王八蛋！
That's enough. You son of a bitch!
嘿 得了吧！
Hey, come on!
我没事 行了
I'm cool, i'm cool. Hey, hey.
够了
That's enough. he's not cut out for this mission.
-他不够资格执行这次任务 -够了！
That's enough! You know it.
你明明知道的
你知道我是对的
You know i'm right.
全体解散
You're all dismissed.
冰人：我得见见你
现在不太方便
冰人：我没在征求你的同意
独行侠
Maverick.
又复发了？
It's come back?
没人知道
No one knows.
能做的我们都做了
There's nothing else they can do.
他连说话都很痛苦
Even speaking is painful now.
莎拉 真的很遗憾
Sarah, i'm so sorry.
上将
Admiral.
我的僚机驾驶员还好吗？
How's my wingman?
我想谈谈工作
拜托 别担心我
Please, Don't worry about me.
我能做什么？
What can I do for you?
好吧
All right.
公鸡还在为我做的事生气
Well, rooster's still angry with me about what I did.
我本以为他有一天能理解
I thought eventually he would understand why.
也希望他能原谅我
I hoped he'd forgive me.
还有时间
任务只剩下不到三个星期
The mission is less than three weeks away.
那孩子没准备好
The kid's not ready.
那就教好他
我要教的东西他不想学
He doesn't want what I have to give.
冰人 拜托
Ice, please,
别要求我派别人去赴死
Don't ask me to send someone else to die.
别这么做…
Please Don't...
别要我派他去
Don't ask me to send him.
派我去吧
Send me.
该放手了
我不知道该如何放手
I Don't know how.
我是不当教官的料 冰人
I'm not a teacher, ice.
我是战斗机驾驶员
I'm a fighter pilot.
海军飞行员
A naval aviator.
那不仅仅是我的工作
It's not what I am.
而是我的人生
It's who I am.
我该怎么教这种事？
How do I teach that?
就算可以 也不是公鸡要的
Even if I could teach it, it's not what rooster wants.
更不是海军要的
It's not what the Navy wants.
所以上次我才会受到处罚
That's why they canned me the last time.
我之所以还能在海军是因为你
The only reason i'm here is you.
如果我派他参加这项任务
If I send him on this mission,
他可能就此一去不回
he might never come home.
但若不派他去
And if I Don't send him,
他绝对不会原谅我
he'll never forgive me.
不管怎样我都将永远失去他
Either way, I could lose him forever.
我知道
I know.
海军需要独行侠
The Navy needs Maverick.
那孩子需要独行侠
The kid needs Maverick.
所以我才极力为你争取
That's why I fought for you.
所以你才能依然留在海军
That's why you're still here.
谢谢你 冰人
Thank you, ice,
为我所做的一切
for everything.
最后一件事
One last thing.
谁是比较厉害的飞行员？
Who's the better pilot?
你还是我？
You or me?
现在气氛还不错 别破坏了
This is a nice moment. Let's not ruin it.
好吧
All right, all right.
触地得分！
swimmin' in the floodstouchdown!
长官
Sir.
-这是在做什么？-橄榄球恶战
What is this? This is dogfight football.
同时进攻和防守
Offense and defense at the same time.
谁领先？
Who's winning?
他们早就没在计分了
I think they stopped keeping score a while ago.
这批特遣队还需要训练 上校
This detachment still has some training to complete, captain.
-每分每秒都很重要 -是 长官
Every available minute matters. Yes, sir.
那为什么还在打球？
So why are we out here playing games?
你说要团队合作 长官
You said to create a team, sir.
那就是你的团队
There's your team.
我是不是该走了？趁着阿米莉亚还没回来？
Should I go? Before Amelia gets back?
-她要在朋友家过夜 -那就好
She'll be at her friend's house tonight. Oh, good.
你和阿米莉亚看起来…
You and Amelia, you seem...
比之前更亲密
A lot closer than when I last saw you.
-是啊 我们确实如此 -怎么做到的？
Yeah. Yeah, we are. How do you manage?
这个嘛
Well,
她一直要我给她更多的自由
you know, she always wanted more freedom than I thought she was ready for.
不知道这一点是遗传到谁？
Hmm. Where'd she get that from, I wonder?
我意识到
I guess I realized
我也必须信任她
I also had to trust her.
偶尔让她自己犯些错
Let her make some of her own mistakes sometimes.
这决定不容易
Not an easy choice.Mmm.
你和公鸡也是这样吗？
Is that what happened with rooster?
我抽掉他的海军学院申请书
I pulled his papers from the naval academy.
浪费了他几年时间
Took years off his career.
为什么？
Why?
笨鹅死后 他母亲不希望他当飞行员
His mother never wanted him to fly, not after what happened to goose.
她死前要我答应她 所以…
She made me promise before she died, so...
公鸡知道吗？
Does rooster know that?
他永远会为这件事恨我
He will always resent me for what I did.
我为何让他也恨自己的妈妈呢？
Why should he resent her too?
这决定不容易
Not an easy choice.Hmm.
他失去父亲后 我试着去充当那个角色
I was trying to be the father he lost.
只是…
I just...
我希望能做得更好
I wish I would've done it better.
但是事实是
But the truth is...
我当时认为他还没准备好
I didn't think he was ready.
那现在他准备好了吗？
Is he ready now?
妈 我回家了！
Mom, i'm home!
我以为你要在凯伦家过夜
I thought you were staying at Karen's tonight.
凯伦生病了 我有作业要写
Karen's sick. And i've got homework to do.
-我该走了 -你该走了
I should go. you should go.
-你吃过饭没？-还没 要出去吃吗？
Have you had dinner yet? not yet. You wanna go out?
没关系 我做给你吃
No, it's okay. I'll make you something.
马上就下去！
I'll be down in a sec!
-等等！别走那儿 -什么？
Wait! Not that way. What?
听着 我得当个好榜样
Look, I have an example to set.
不能第一次约会就带男人回家
I can't be bringing guys home on a first date.
这不是第一次约会
This is not our first date.
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
好吧
Okay.
Fine.
这是我最后一次从你家的窗户跳出去
But this is the last time I go out your window.
这可不好说
We'll see.
不 我认真的
No. No, I mean it.
我永远不会再离开你
I'm never gonna leave you again.
闭嘴吧
Oh, shut up.
快走吧
Go on, get out of here.
别再伤她的心
Just Don't break her heart again.
早上好
Good morning.
你们的目标铀浓缩工厂
The uranium enrichment plant that is your target
将会比预期提早开始运作
will be operational earlier than expected.
原铀会在十天后送到工厂
Raw uranium will be delivered to the plant in ten days' time.
所以你们的任务也提前一星期
As a result, your mission has been moved up one week
以免那座峡谷受到辐射污染
in order to avoid contaminating the target valley with radiation.
长官 这里没人成功完成过低空航道飞行
Sir, no one here has successfully flown a low-level course.
尽管如此 你们的命令仍是继续执行任务
Nevertheless, you've been ordered to move on.
上校
Captain.
只剩一星期进行第二阶段演练
We have one week left to focus on phase two.
那是这项任务最困难的阶段
It's the most difficult stage of the mission.
也就是爬升突袭 加俯冲攻击
It's a pop-up strike with a steep dive,
需要连续出现两个奇迹
requiring nothing less than two consecutive miracles.
两组战斗机要以并列队形飞行
Two pairs of f-18s will fly
in a welded wing formation.
团队合作
Teamwork. Precise coordination of these aircraft is essential
飞行的精准度
是这项任务成功和你们存活的关键
to both the mission's success and your survival.
工厂坐落在两座山脉之间
As you know, the plant rests between two mountains.
逼近时要头朝下直接俯冲
On final approach, you'll invert directly into a steep dive.
这样才能保持低空飞行
This allows you to maintain the lowest possible altitude
也是唯一的攻击角度
and the only possible attack angle.
目标的弹着点不到三米宽
Your target is an impact point less than three meters wide.
两人座战斗机将以激光标示靶点
The two-seat aircraft will paint the target
with a laser bull's-eye.
第一组将发射激光引导导弹
The first pair will breach the reactor
进入通风口炸毁反应炉
by dropping a laser-guided bomb on an exposed ventilation hatch.
这会为第二组制造空档
This will create an opening for the second pair.
那是第一个奇迹
That's miracle number one.
第二组
The second team will deliver the kill shot...
将做出必杀一击
并摧毁目标
And destroy the target.
那是第二个奇迹
That's miracle number two.
两组都没有命中目标…
If either team misses the target...
没打中
That's a miss. The mission is a failure.
-任务就失败了 -可恶！
Damn it!
飞离时必须高G力爬升以免撞到山壁
Egress is a steep high-g climb out
to avoid hitting this mountain.
高G力爬升至少会承受8个G力
A steep climb at that speed, you're pulling at least eight g's.
至少9个G力
Nine, minimum.
F-18机身的极限应力是7.5
The stress limit of the f-18's airframe is 7.5.
那是可接受的极限
That's the accepted limit.
想活着回来就得超越极限
To survive this mission, you'll pull beyond that,
就算必须折弯机身
even if it means bending your airframe.
重力大到你们会重达900公斤
You'll be pulling so hard, you'll weigh close to 2,000 pounds,
头盖骨会挤压脊椎
your skull crushing your spine...
像被一头大象坐在胸口挤压肺部
Your lungs imploding like an elephant's sitting on your chest,
拼了命也要避免昏死过去
fighting with everything you have just to keep from blacking out.
这是你们最脆弱的时刻
And this is where you'll be at your most vulnerable.
这就是棺材角
This is coffin corner.
就算你们没撞上山壁
Assuming you avoid crashing into this mountain,
也会爬升到敌军雷达范围内 同时完全失速
you'll climb straight up into enemy radar while losing all of your airspeed.
这时候将遇到敌军地对空导弹攻击
Within seconds, you'll be fired upon by enemy sams.
你们都承受过G力 但这次…
You've all faced sustained g's before, but this...
将把你们和战斗机逼到临界点
This is gonna take you and your aircraft to the breaking point.
长官 这任务有可能成功吗？
Sir, is this even achievable?
这个问题的答案
The answer to that question
取决于驾驶舱内的飞行员
will come down to the pilot in the box.
-报告状况 鲍勃 -我们落后12秒
Talk to me, Bob. We are 12 seconds late on target.
-必须加速！-收到 试着跟上来
We gotta move! We gotta move! Copy. Try to stay with me.
等等 那是谁？
Huh? Wait, who's that?
蓝队 你们被侦测到
Blue team, you've been spotted.
-我去 是独行侠 -他跑来干嘛？
Shit, it's Maverick. What the hell is he doing here?
我是来拦截的敌机 蓝队 你们要怎么办？
I'm a bandit on course to intercept. Blue team, what are you gonna do?
他在20英里之外 10点钟方向 速度700节
He's 20 miles left. Ten o'clock. 700 knots closure.
你决定 你要怎么做？
Your call. What do you want to do?
继续下去 就快接近目标了
Continue. We're close. Stay on target.
-他绕到北方了！-准备爬升
He's swinging around to the north! Stand by for pop-up.
-准备激光引导导弹 鲍勃 -收到 正在准备
Be ready on that laser, Bob.Copy. I'm on it.
蓝队 敌机逼近中
Blue team, bandit is still closing.
爬升
Popping now.
报告状况 鲍勃 独行侠呢？
Talk to me, Bob. Where's Maverick?
5英里外 快速逼近
He's five miles out. He's coming fast.
-看到目标 -激光呢 鲍勃？
Target's in sight. Where's my laser, Bob?
无法瞄准！抱歉 无法锁定目标
Deadeye! Deadeye! It's no good. Sorry, I can't get a lock.
来不及了 我要盲投炸弹
We're out of time. I'm dropping blind.
该死 没打中！
Damn it, missed!
-锁定你了 -独行侠的导弹锁定我们了
That's tone.
Maverick's got missile lock on us. Shit! We're dead.
可恶！我们死了
蓝队 任务失败 停止爬升 郊狼
Blue team, that's a fail.
Level out, coyote.
郊狼？收到了吗？
Coyote? Do you copy?
郊狼 回答
Coyote, come in.
郊狼 拉直
Coyote, level wings.
天啊 他陷入G力昏迷了
Oh, god. He's in g-loc.
郊狼？
Coyote? Coyote?
-他会坠机的！-我去追他
He's gonna burn in! I'm going after him.
快啊 快点锁定
Come on. Give me tone, give me tone, give me tone.
快醒醒 郊狼 快啊！
Snap out of it, coyote. Come on! Come on!
加油 郊狼！
Come on, coyote, come on. Come on!
-该死 郊狼！-爬升！
- Damn it! Coyote! - Coyote! pull up!
-郊狼！-爬升！
Coyote! Coyote! Pull up! Pull up!
郊狼 没事吧？
Coyote, you okay? You okay?
我没事
I'm okay. I'm good.
那就好 今天的演练就到这里
Good. Good. That's enough for today.
真是好险
That was close.
太危险了
Too close.
飞鸟撞击！
Bird strike! Bird strike!
Bird strike!
-凤凰 左引擎起火！-爬升
Phoenix, left engine's on fire! Climbing.
减速 关闭左引擎燃油
Throttling back. Shutting off fuel to left engine.
灭火
Extinguishing fire.
右引擎故障！
Right engine is out!
涡轮还在旋转 试图重新启动
It's still spinning. Trying to restart it.
-凤凰 引擎起火时别启动 -加速
Phoenix, it's on fire.
Don't start... throttling up.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
-起火了！-该死！
We're on fire! We're on fire! Damn it!
-右引擎起火 -熄灭右引擎
Engine fire. Right. Extinguishing right engine.
凤凰 鲍勃 快弹射！
Phoenix, Bob, punch out, punch out!
警示灯都亮着！液压系统失灵！
Warning lights everywhere! Hydraulic failure!
-操纵失效 -我无法控制了
Flight controls. I can't control it.
我们要坠机了！凤凰！
We're going down, Phoenix! We're going in! We're going in!
没救了 快弹射！
You can't save it. Eject, eject!
弹射！
Eject, eject, eject!
高度
Altitude. Altitude.
凤凰和鲍勃要在医院过夜接受观察
They'll keep Phoenix and Bob in the hospital overnight for observation.
他们不会有事
They're gonna be okay.
那就好
That's good.
我从未失去过僚机
I've never lost a wingman.
你很幸运
You're lucky.
飞得够久 就会发生这种事
Fly long enough, it'll happen.
会有其他人
There will be others.
你说得倒容易 没有老婆
Easy for you to say. No wife.
没有小孩
No kids.
坠机了也不会有人悼念你
Nobody to mourn you when you burn in.
回家吧
Go home.
好好睡个觉
Just get some sleep.
你为什么抽掉我在学院的申请书？
Why'd you pull my papers at the academy?
为什么挡我的路？
Why did you stand in my way?
你当时还没准备好
You weren't ready.
准备好什么？
Ready for what?
-像你那样飞？-不
Huh? Ready to fly like you? No.
准备忘记书本里的规则
Ready to forget the book.
相信直觉 别多想 去做就是了
Trust your instincts. Don't think, just do.
飞行时多想就会死掉 相信我
You think up there, you're dead. Believe me.
我爸就相信过你
My dad believed in you.
但我不会犯同样的错
I'm not gonna make the same mistake.
独行侠
Maverick.
准备 瞄准 开火
Ready, aim, fire.
准备
Ready,
瞄准
aim,
开火
fire.
准备
Ready,
瞄准
aim,
开火
fire.
我无法体会你现在的感受
I can only imagine what you must be feeling right now.
休息几天吧 怎样都行
Take some time. Whatever you need.
谢谢你 长官 但是任务…
I appreciate that, sir, but there is no time. The mission...
我会接手训练他们
I'll be taking over the training from here.
长官？
Sir?
我们都知道你不想要这份工作
We both know you didn't want this job, captain.
-他们还没准备好 -你的职责就是让他们准备好
Sir, they're not ready. It was your job to get them ready.
他们必须相信能完成这项任务
Sir, they have to believe that this mission can be flown.
你却只让他们认为任务会失败
And all you've managed to do is teach them that it can't.
-长官… -你被禁飞了 上校
Sir... you're grounded, captain.
永远禁飞
Permanently.
-长官… -就这样
Sir... that is all.
我听说了
I heard.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你有什么打算？
What are you gonna do?
冰人走了
Ice is gone.
我还能有什么选择？
What choice do I have?
你会找到继续飞的方法
You'll have to find a way back on your own.
不 潘妮
No, penny.
我已经出局了
I'm out.
都结束了
This is over.
彼得
Pete.
空战时 你就算失去僚机
If you lost your wingman up there,
还是会继续奋战
you'd keep fighting.
你才不会就这么放弃
You wouldn't just give up.
他们是你的飞行员
Those are your pilots.
要是他们出什么事
If anything happens to them,
你会永远无法原谅自己
you'll never forgive yourself.
我不知道该怎么做
I Don't know what to do.
但你会找到方法的
But you'll find a way.
我知道你一定会的
I know you will.
米契尔上校不再是你们的教官
Captain Mitchell is no longer your instructor.
从今天起有新的任务参数
And as of today, there are new mission parameters.
抵达目标时间现在变为4分钟
Time to target is now four minutes.
你们将减速飞入峡谷
You'll be entering the valley level at reduced speed.
不准超过420节
Not to exceed 420 knots.
长官 那敌机不就有时间进行拦截了？
Sir, won't we be giving their planes time to intercept?
对上敌机至少还有机会存活
Well, lieutenant, you have a fighting chance against enemy aircraft.
撞上山壁存活的机率是多少？
What are the odds of surviving a head-on collision with a mountain?
你们要沿着北边山壁
You'll be attacking the target from a higher altitude,
从更高的高度攻击目标
level with the north wall.
这会更难以激光标示目标
Gonna be a little harder to keep your lase on target,
但能避免高G力爬升
but you will avoid the high-g climb out.
那就成了敌方导弹的活靶子了
We'll be sitting ducks for enemy missiles.
那是谁？
Who the hell is that?
独行侠呼叫控制中心 进入A点
Maverick to range control. Entering point Alpha.
请确认安全范围
Confirm green range.
独行侠 这里是控制中心
Uh, Maverick, range control, uh, green range is confirmed.
确认安全
我没看到你的演练行程
I Don't see an event scheduled for you, sir.
我还是要去
Well, i'm going anyway.
有好戏看了
Nice.
设定目标时间：2分15秒
Setting time to target:
Two minutes 15 seconds.
2分15秒？不可能
2:15? That's impossible.
飞往最终攻击点 独行侠已就位
Final attack point. Maverick's inbound.
倒数三、二、一 爬升
Popping in three, two, one.
炸弹已投掷
Bombs away.
正中目标！我的天啊！
Bull's-eye! Holy shit!
好厉害
Yes.
太牛了
Damn.
你让我左右为难 上校
You have put me in a difficult position, captain.
你一方面示范了任务的可行性
On the one hand, you have demonstrated that this mission can be flown.
也许是唯一存活的方法
Perhaps the only way it can be survived.
另一方面
On the other hand,
你偷偷开走一架数百万美元的陆军战斗机
you did it by stealing a multimillion-dollar military aircraft
在飞行中把它损耗到可能永远无法再飞行
and flying it in such a manner that it may never be airworthy again.
冰人不能再保护你了
Iceman is no longer here to protect you.
我大可以把你送去军事法庭
I have everything I need to have you court-martialed
把你开除军籍
and dishonorably discharged.
我该怎么做？
So what do I do?
冒着飞行员阵亡和任务失败的风险
Risk the lives of my pilots
and perhaps the success of this mission
或者…
or...
赌上我的军旅生涯
Risk my career
任命你为任务队长？
by appointing you team leader?
长官…
Sir...
我觉得中将没有真的在问你问题 上校
I think the admiral's asking a rhetorical question, captain.
你要在就好了 笨鹅
Talk to me, goose.
米契尔上校！
Captain Mitchell!
这是你施展身手的地方
You're where you belong.
让我们以你为荣吧
Make us proud.
很荣幸能与你们飞行
It has been an honor flying with you.
各位都是精英中的精英
Each one of you represents the best of the best.
这项任务非常有针对性
This is a very specific mission.
我的选择完全仰仗这一点
My choice is a reflection of that and nothing more.
挑选两组F小队队员
Choose your two foxtrot teams.
复仇者和粉小子
Payback and fanboy.
凤凰和鲍勃
Phoenix and Bob.
你的僚机驾驶员
And your wingman.
公鸡
Rooster.
其他人在航母待命
The rest of you will stand by on the carrier
随时准备支援
for any reserve role that's required.
解散
Dismissed.
你们的目标是明显且迫切的威胁
Your target is a clear and present threat.
受到敌国掌控的秘密铀浓缩工厂
A secret uranium enrichment site under rogue state control.
位于地下碉堡
It's an underground bunker,
坐落在这两座山脉之间
tucked between these two mountains.
进攻航道受到地对空导弹的森严防卫
Your route of ingress is heavily defended by surface-to-air missiles
另有第五代战斗机支援
backed up by fifth-generation fighters.
F-18突击队一旦跨越边界
Once your f-18 strike team crosses the border,
莱特湾号航空母舰
tomahawk missiles from the USS Leyte Gulf
就会同步发射战斧导弹攻击这座机场
will launch a synchronized strike on the enemy's airfield here.
炸毁那里的跑道
This will knock out their runway.
但你们还得对付已经升空的战斗机
But you'll have to contend with any planes already in the air.
战斧导弹击中后 敌方就知道你们来了
The moment those tomahawks hit, the enemy will know you're coming.
抵达目标时间是2分30秒
Your time to target
will be two minutes and 30 seconds.
超过时间就会遭到
Any longer than that, and you will be exposed
战斧导弹没击中的战斗机攻击
to any aircraft the tomahawks may have missed.
这是你们受训的目的
This is what you've all been training for.
安全归来
Come home safely.
给他们点颜色看看！
You give 'em hell!
长官
Sir.
长官？
Sir?
我…
I...
我只想说…
I just want to say...
等回来之后
We'll talk
我们再聊
when we get back.
嘿 布拉德利！
Hey, Bradley! Bradley!
嘿
Hey.
你能搞定的
You got this.
独行侠
Maverick.
独行侠？
Maverick?
嘿 你还好吧？
Hey, you with me?
我不喜欢你这种表情 独行侠
I Don't like that look, mav.
我只有这一种表情
It's the only one I got.
谢谢你
Thank you.
要是我不能再见到你 杭多
If I Don't see you again, hondo,
谢谢你
thank you.
这是我的荣幸 上校
It's been an honor, captain.
匕首一号 在一号弹射器已就绪
Dagger one, up and ready on catapult one.
匕首候补 待命中
Dagger spare standing by.
匕首四号 已就绪
Dagger four, up and ready.
匕首三号 已就绪
Dagger three, up and ready.
匕首二号 已就绪
Dagger two, up and ready.
支援军机起飞 突击队已就绪
Support assets airborne.
Strike package ready.
等待起飞指令
Standing by for launch decision.
出发
Send them.
匕首二号 起飞
Dagger two away.
匕首三号 起飞
Dagger three away.
匕首四号 起飞
Dagger four away.
科曼奇 匕首一号 等候情况汇报
Comanche, dagger one. Standby check in.
科曼奇11号预警机已就位
Comanche 11, set.
空域安全 建议匕首小队继续任务
Picture clean. Recommend dagger continue.
收到 匕首小队低空飞行
Copy. Daggers descending below radar.
匕首小队低于雷达 切换至鹰眼图像
Daggers now below radar. Switching to e-2 picture.
来吧 前方是敌方领地
Here we go. Enemy territory up ahead.
60秒后登陆 科曼奇 匕首一号请求状况汇报
Feet dry in 60 seconds. Comanche, dagger one. Picture.
前方安全 决定权交给你
Comanche. Picture clean. Decision is yours.
收到
Copy.
展开攻击
Dagger attack.
战斧导弹已经发射
Tomahawks airborne.
现在已经没有回头路了
No turning back now.
匕首小队 组成进攻队形
Daggers, assume attack formation.
匕首小队准备就绪 前往目标
Daggers set. Proceeding to target.
2分30秒 三、二、一 计时开始
Two minutes and 30 seconds in three, two, one, Mark.
-二号计时开始 -三号计时开始
Two Mark. Three Mark.
四号计时开始
Four Mark.
进入峡谷
Going in.
飞过第一个地对空导弹阵地
First Sam site overhead.
貌似我们未被雷达侦测到 独行侠
Looks like we're clear on radar, mav.
别掉以轻心
Let's not take it for granted.
更多地对空导弹！3点钟方向！
More sams! Three o'clock high!
-2分钟后抵达目标 -收到
We got two minutes to target. copy.
我们落后了几秒 公鸡 得快点
We're a few seconds behind, rooster. We got to move.
战斧导弹将于30秒后击中敌方跑道
Thirty seconds to tomahawk impact on enemy airstrip.
匕首小队 科曼奇
Dagger, comanche.
我们侦测到两架敌机 组成一对
We're picking up two bandits. Single group, two contacts.
-他们从哪来的？-长程巡逻？
Where the hell'd they come from? Long-range patrol?
科曼奇 它们的航向是什么？
Comanche, what's their heading?
航向090 目标西南50英里
Bull's-eye 090, 50, tacked southwest.
它们没看到我们 飞走了
They're headed away from us. They Don't know we're here.
战斧导弹一击中空军基地
The second those tomahawks hit the air base,
敌机就会折返防卫目标
those bandits are gonna move to defend the target.
我们得抢先一步 加速
We have to get there before they do. Increase speed.
我们会跟上 独行侠 别等我
We got you, mav. Don't wait for me.
长官 匕首二号和四号进度落后
Sir, daggers two and four are behind schedule.
抵达目标时间 1分20秒
Time to target, one minute 20.
离战斧导弹击中目标时间还剩 三、二…
Tomahawk impact in three, two...
击中目标 敌方机场跑道已摧毁
Impact. Enemy runway is destroyed.
他们现在知道我们来了
They know we're coming now.
敌机转向 前去保护目标
Bandits are switching course to defend the target.
公鸡 你在哪？
Rooster, where are you?
快点 公鸡 敌机已调头回巢
Come on, rooster. Bandits inbound.
我们得赶上 来吧 豁出去了
We got to make up time now. Let's turn and burn.
小心 凤凰
Heads up, Phoenix.
长官 敌机距离目标2分钟 匕首小队1分钟
Sir, bandits are two minutes from target.
Daggers are one minute from target.
快啊 公鸡 不快点就完蛋了
Come on, rooster. Move it or lose it.
我们落后了 真的得加速
Guys, we're falling behind. We really gotta move.
现在不加速
If we Don't increase our speed right now,
敌机就会在目标那里等着我们
those bandits are gonna be waiting for us when we reach the target.
爸 我该怎么做
Talk to me, dad.
加油 你行的
Come on, kid, you can do it.
别多想 去做就是了
Don't think, just do.
天啊 公鸡 也不用这么快吧！
Jesus, rooster, not that fast!
这就对了 小子 好 咱们上吧
That's it, kid, that's it. All right, let's go.
好家伙 公鸡 悠着点
Damn, rooster, take it easy.
匕首二号赶上来了
Sir, dagger two is reengaging.
很好 击中目标 然后安全归来
All right, now hit your target and come home.
30秒后抵达目标 鲍勃 检查激光情况
Thirty seconds to target. Bob, check your laser.
检查完毕 确认激光辨识码 1688
Air-to-ground check complete. Laser code verified, 1688.
激光准备就绪！
Laser is a go!
注意上方
Watch your heads.
我去！
Holy shit! Shit!
-复仇者 跟上了吗？-在你后方
Payback, you with me? Right behind you.
凤凰 准备好爬升突袭
Phoenix, stand by for pop-up strike.
匕首三号就位
Dagger three in position.
倒数三、二、一 爬升
Popping in three, two, one.
-标示目标 鲍勃 -匕首三号
Get me eyes on that target, Bob. Dagger three.
待命 独行侠
Stand by, mav. Come on, Bob, come on.
-快啊 鲍勃 -待命
Stand by.
-搞定 目标已标示！-锁定目标 投掷炸弹
I've got it. Captured! Target acquired. Bombs away.
我们击中了！确认直接命中目标！
We've got impact! Check, direct hit! Direct hit!
那是第一个奇迹
That's miracle number one.
匕首二号 情况汇报
Dagger two, status.
就快到了
Almost there, mav. Almost there.
粉小子 激光呢？
Fanboy, where's my laser?
公鸡 激光出了问题
Rooster, there's something wrong with this laser!
该死！无法瞄准！
Shit! Deadeye, deadeye, deadeye!
快点 没时间了 快点修好！
Come on, guys, we're running out of time. Get it online!
-我正在试！-快点 粉小子！
I'm trying! Come on, fanboy!
就快好了！
Nearly there! Nearly there!
-快点搞定 粉小子 -来不及了 我要盲投了
Come on, fanboy, get it online. There's no time. I'm dropping blind.
-公鸡 我行的！-来不及了 快投吧
Rooster, I got this! No time. Pull up.
-等等！-投掷炸弹！
Wait! Bombs away! Bombs away!
正中目标！
Bull's-eye, bull's-eye, bull's-eye!
第二个奇迹
Miracle number two.
他们飞到棺材角了
Now they're in coffin corner.
还没脱险
We're not out of this yet.
大家小心
Here it comes.
雷达警告！导弹来袭！凤凰 向右急转
Radar warning! Smoke in the air. Phoenix, break right.
紧急投弃 匕首三号进行闪避
Emergency jettison. Dagger three defending.
又来一枚导弹！
Here comes another one!
匕首一号进行闪避
Dagger one defending.
公鸡 汇报情况
Rooster, status.
天啊
Oh, my god.
导弹来袭！
Smoke in the air! Smoke in the air!
-向右急转 复仇者！-向右急转
Break right, payback! Breaking right.
天啊 又来了！
Oh, my god, here they come!
公鸡 你正后方有地对空导弹！
Sam on your six, rooster!
部署应对措施
Deploying countermeasures.
未被击中
Negative contact.
匕首一号进行闪避
Dagger one defending.
-汇报状况 鲍勃 -向右急转 凤凰！向右急转 独行侠！
Talk to me, Bob. Break right, Phoenix! Break right! Mav!
9点钟方向！
Nine o'clock! Nine o'clock!
公鸡 两枚在你正后方
Rooster, two more on your six.
匕首二号 进行闪避
Dagger two, defending.
-复仇者 正前方有地对空导弹 -匕首四号进行闪避
Payback, Sam on your nose. Dagger four defending.
-公鸡 7点钟方向！-汇报状况 鲍勃！
Rooster, tally, seven o'clock! Talk to me, Bob!
-在正后方！-匕首二号进行闪避
On our six! Dagger two defending.
-凤凰 向右急转！-我看到了！
Phoenix, break right! I see it!
匕首二号进行闪避
Dagger two defending.
糟糕 我没热诱弹了！
Shit, i'm out of flares!
公鸡 回避！
Rooster, evade, evade!
我甩不掉！它们锁定我了！
I can't shake 'em! They're on me! They're on me!
独行侠！不！
Mav! No!
匕首一号中弹！重复 匕首一号中弹！
Dagger one is hit! I repeat, dagger one is hit!
独行侠被击落
Maverick is down.
匕首一号 汇报情况
Dagger one, status.
汇报情况！
Status!
有谁看到他吗？
Anyone see him? Does anyone see him?
-匕首一号 请讲话！-我没看到降落伞
Dagger one, come in! I didn't see a parachute.
我们得绕回去
We have to circle back.
这里是科曼奇预警机 敌机来袭 组成一对 准备攻击
Comanche. Bandits inbound. Single group, hot.
建议匕首小队往南飞
Recommend dagger flow south.
一分钟后拦截
One minute to intercept.
现在就叫他们返回航母
Get 'em back to the carrier now. All daggers flow to ecp.
匕首小队返回基地 敌机正朝你们飞来
You have bandits headed for you. What about Maverick?
那独行侠呢？
跟他说他帮不了独行侠什么 驾驶F-18打不过敌机的
Tell him there's nothing he can do for Maverick, not in a goddamn f-18.
匕首后备要求进行空中支援
Dagger spare request permission to launch and fly air cover.
不准
Negative, spare.
-展开搜救行动 -不准 空中有敌机
Launch search and rescue.
Negative. Not with bandits in the air.
-长官 但独行侠还活着 -今天不能再损失任何人
But, sir, Maverick is still out there.
We are not losing anyone else today.
命令他们回来
Get 'em home now.
匕首小队 不准交火
Dagger, you are not to engage.
重复 不准交火
Repeat, do not engage.
匕首二号返回航母 确认
Dagger two, return to carrier. Acknowledge.
确认
Acknowledge.
公鸡 敌机正在逼近 我们不能回去
Rooster, those bandits are closing.
We can't go back.
公鸡 他死了
Rooster, he's gone.
独行侠死了
Maverick's gone.
不
Oh, no, no.
匕首二号被击中
Dagger two is hit.
匕首二号 请讲话
Dagger two, come in.
匕首二号 收到吗？
Dagger two, do you copy?
匕首二号 汇报
Dagger two, come in.
你没事吧？
You all right?
我没事 你呢？
Yeah, i'm good. You all right?
搞什么？
What the hell? What are you doing here?
-你来干嘛？-我来干嘛？
What am I doing here? You think I took that missile
你觉得我替你挡那枚导弹 是为了让你也被打下来陪我？
so you could be down here with me?
你早就该飞回航母了！
You should be back on the carrier by now!
我救了你一命！
I saved your life!
我救了你 那才是重点
I saved your life. That's the whole point.
你到底在想什么？
What the hell were you even thinking?
你叫我不要多想！
You told me not to think!
不过呢
Well,
见到你真好
it's good to see you.
我也是
It's good to see you too.
有什么计划？
So what's the plan?
你不是认真的吧？
You're not serious.
你肯定在开玩笑
You've got to be shitting me.
F-14战斗机？
An f-14?
我开那玩意击落过三架米格战斗机
I shot down three migs in one of those.
那块破铜烂铁能不能飞我们都不知道
We Don't even know if that bag of ass can fly.
-去看看就知道了 -独行侠！
Let's find out. Mav!
好吧
Okay.
-前面有人 -是啊
There's guys up there, mav.Yeah.
-那里有更多人 -好
There's more over there. okay.
-开始跑吧 -好啊 跑起来
Let's start running. yeah, run. Run.
等我给你打信号准备升空后
Once... once I give you the signal for air,
打开这开关 直到指针指到120
you're gonna flip this switch until the needle gets to 120.
引擎启动后
When the engine starts,
你就把连接头拔出来 断开所有连接
you got to pull out the pins and disconnect everything.
-你明白了吗？-明白
You understand? Yeah.
太棒了！
Yes!
我一上去就收起梯子
Once i'm up, stow the ladder.
好吧 好家伙
Okay. Wow.
很久没开了 是吧 独行侠
It's been a minute, huh, mav?
天啊 这玩意简直是老古董
Oh, my god. This thing is so old.
好吧
All right.
-可否关闭座舱罩 ？-可以
Canopy? Clear.
两条跑道都坑坑洼洼的
Both runways are cratered.
该怎么让这博物馆里的玩意儿起飞？
How we gonna get this museum piece in the air?
你为什么延展机翼？
Why are the wings coming out, mav?
这是滑行道 不是跑道
Mav, this is a taxiway, not a runway.
而且是很短的滑行道
This is a very short taxiway, mav.
坐好了
Just hang on.
我的妈呀！
Holy shit!
快点
Come on, come on, come on.
指针能运作
Needle's alive. Come on.
-独行侠？-不错 快点！
Mav? That's it. Come on, come on!
很好
All right.
-独行侠！-起飞了
Mav! Here we go.
天啊
Holy shit.
长官 收到公鸡的信号
Sir, we're receiving a signal from rooster's esat.
看起来是故障
But there seems to be a malfunction.
-信号又消失了？-不是
Have you lost him? No, sir.
他现在的状态是超音速
He's supersonic.
他在飞行
He's airborne.
-用什么飞？-长官
In what? Sir.
侦察机汇报一架F-14战机正在飞来
Overwatch reports an f-14 tomcat is airborne and on course for our position.
不可能 怎么可能！
Can't be. It can't be!
是独行侠
Maverick.
公鸡 联络一下航母
Okay, rooster, get us in touch with the boat.
我正在试
I'm working on it.
无线电坏掉了 没有雷达 我这里没有什么能用的
Radio's out. No radar. Everything's dead back here.
-我要怎么做？教教我 -先是无线电
What do I do? Talk me through it. Okay, first the radio.
安上…
Throw the, uh...
试试那个
The uhf-2 circuit breaker. Try that.
有一大堆断路器 可以再具体一点吗？
There's 300 breakers back here. Anything more specific?
我不知道 那是你爸擅长的领域
I Don't know. That was your dad's department.
我会弄清楚的
I'll figure it out.
独行侠 两架敌机在下方5点钟方向
Mav, tally two, 5:00 low.
该怎么办？
What do we do?
听着 保持冷静就好
Okay, listen. Just be cool.
如果我们暴露了身份 估计早就死了
If they knew who we were, we'd be dead already.
他们来了
Well, here they come.
-你打算怎么做？-戴上面罩
What's your plan? Just put your mask on.
记住 我们是同一边的
Remember, we're on the same team.
微笑着挥手就好
Just wave and smile.
那什么信号？他在表达什么？
What's that signal? What's he saying?
没概念 我不知道他在说什么
No idea. I have no idea what he's saying.
-这个呢？也不知道吗？-我也没看过
What about that one? Any idea? No, never seen that one either.
该死 他的僚机进入攻击位置
Oh, shit. His wingman is moving into weapons envelope.
听好了
All right, listen up.
我一下令你就抓住头上的圆环
When I tell you, you grab those rings above your head.
那是弹射把手
That's the ejection handle.
独行侠 我们不能甩开他们吗？
Mav, can we outrun these guys?
他们有导弹和机关枪 我们没戏
Not their missiles and guns.
那就要空战一下了
Then it's a dogfight.
一架F-14 对抗第五代战斗机？
An f-14 against fifth-gen fighters?
关键不在飞机 而是飞行员
It's not the plane, it's the pilot.
我不在你肯定会迎敌
You'd go after 'em if I wasn't here.
但你在啊
But you are here.
别这样 独行侠
Come on, mav.
别多想
Don't think.
去做就是了
Just do.
看到导弹就告诉我
Tell me when you see smoke in the air.
-导弹来袭！-坐好了
Smoke in the air! Smoke in the air! Hang on.
太棒了 独行侠 击落了一架！
Yeah, mav! Splash one! Splash one!
又来一枚导弹
Here comes another one.
公鸡 发射热诱弹！赶紧！
Rooster, flares! Now, now, now!
分配气阀
Splitting the throttles.
绕回去
Coming around.
-快锁定 快锁定啊 -锁定了 独行侠！
Give me tone, give me tone.
You got him, mav! You got him! Taking the shot.
发射导弹
搞什么…
What the...
天啊！刚才是什么情况？
Holy shit! What the fuck was that?
坐好了 我要飞低一点
Hang on. We gotta get low.
峡谷会干扰他的瞄准系统
The terrain will confuse his targeting system.
他来了！
Here he comes!
汇报状况 公鸡 他在哪？
Talk to me, rooster. Where is he?
他仍然穷追不舍！
He's still on us!
-我们被击中了！-该死！
We took a hit! We took a hit! Damn it!
-快展示一下你的飞行技巧 独行侠 -坐好了
Come on, mav. Do some of that pilot shit. Brace yourself.
我的天啊
Holy shit.
锁定了 发射导弹
I Got tone. Taking the shot.
该死！
Damn it!
没导弹了 改用机关枪
Out of missiles. Switching to guns.
快啊 独行侠
Come on, mav, come on.
-击中了！-还没结束
You got him, mav! It's not over yet.
-最后一次机会 -你行的
One last chance. You can do this.
加油 独行侠
Come on, Maverick.
太棒了！击落了第二架！
Yes! Splash two!
-独行侠 我修好无线电了 -好样的
Mav, I got the radio on.Outstanding.
-呼叫航母 -收到
Get us in touch with the boat. Copy that.
天啊
Oh, my god.
这家伙在哪？
Where the hell is this guy?
他在正前方
He's on our nose.
该死 子弹都打光了
Damn it, we're out of ammo.
导弹来袭！公鸡 发射热诱弹！
Smoke in the air! Rooster, flares!
刚才好险
That was close.
我们没有热诱弹了 独行侠
We're out of flares, mav.
该死 他已经追上来了
Shit, he's already on us.
情况不妙
This is not good.
-我们又被击中了！-不
We took another hit! No, no, no, no, no!
我们无法再承受射击了
We can't take much more of this.
我们甩不掉这家伙了 只能弹射
We can't outrun this guy. We got to eject.
-什么？-我们需要高度
What? We need altitude.
我下令就拉下弹射把手
Pull the ejection handles the second I tell you.
-等等 独行侠！-没别的办法
Mav, wait! Rooster, there's no other way.
弹射 快弹射！
Eject, eject, eject!
公鸡 快拉把手 弹射！
Rooster, pull the handle! Eject!
把手拉不动
It's not working!
独行侠！
Mav!
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 笨鹅
I'm sorry, goose.
下午好 女士们先生们 我是你们的大救星
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
This is your savior speaking.
请系好安全带
Please fasten your seat belts,
收起小桌板 调直座椅靠背
return your tray tables to their locked and upright positions...
准备降落
And prepare for landing.
嘿 刽子手 你看起来很帅嘛
Hey, hangman, you look good.
当然了 公鸡 我本来就很帅
I am good, rooster. I'm very good.
航母上见
I'll see you back on deck.
独行侠顺风飞行
Maverick is downwind. No front landing gear.
没有前起落架 没有尾钩 收起阻拦索 架起护网
No tailhook. Pull the cable and raise the barricade.
紧急迫降！架起护网！
Foul deck! Foul deck! Raise the barricade!
快啊！
Go!
别告诉我引擎坏了一个
Please Don't tell me we lost an engine.
-行 那我就不说 -好的
All right, I won't tell you that.Okay.
你还好吧？
You good?
挺好的
Yeah. I'm good.
-你又击落一架敌机 -两架了
Chalked yourself another kill. That makes two.
独行侠击落了五架 他才是王牌
Mav has five.
Makes him an ace.
米契尔上校！
Captain Mitchell! Captain Mitchell!
长官
Sir.
谢谢你救了我的命
Thank you for saving my life.
我爸也会这么做
It's what my dad would've done.
嘿 独行侠
Hey, mav.
吉米
Jimmy.
那个…
Is, uh...
潘妮在吗？
Is penny around?
她带阿米莉亚驾驶帆船出海了
Uh, she took Amelia on a sailing trip.
她说过什么时候回来吗？
Did she say when she'd be back?
她还真没提过
You know, she didn't.
你要喝点什么吗？
Can I get you anything?
手伸进去
Get in there.
谨以此片深切缅怀托尼·斯科特